Robert Alvarez

Accounts Payable specialists

Lakewood, CA 90715 robertalvarez6_n43@indeedemail.com 626/409-4012

Well-organized, results oriented professional and (10) years of accounting experience.

A resourceful, team oriented proven the ability to successfully manage and carry out a wide variety of financial responsibilities. Excellent interpersonal skills in dealing with all levels of management and Personnel.

#readytowork

Work Experience

Accounts Payable

Golden Rain Foundation September 2013 to March 2020

• A/ P Matched invoices (two & three)

match for multiple (16) entities.

- Printed, matched and reviewed checks and corresponding back-up weekly.
- Issued manual checks as necessary to accommodate urgent payment requests.
- · Issued stop payments and voided checks, ensuring that replacements were issued if needed.
- Performed research as needed to reconcile vendor statements to the purchase order and to help resolve receipt/invoicing discrepancies allowing for prompt payment.
- . Audit preparation.
- . Prepare 1099's.

.

Accounts Payable Specialist

Metrolink - SCRRA May 2005 to December 2012

Administered electronic Accounts Payable Inbox, ensuring that documentation needed to process payment was available to the entire department.

- Matched invoices (two & three way) within the Oracle system, ensuring compliance with company policies regarding receiving reports, approvals and accounting coding prior to submitting for validation.
- Printed, matched and reviewed checks and corresponding back-up weekly.
- Issued manual checks as necessary to accommodate urgent payment requests.
- · Issued stop payments and voided checks, ensuring that replacements were issued if needed.

- Performed research as needed to reconcile vendor statements to the purchase order and to help resolve receipt/invoicing discrepancies allowing for prompt payment.
- Ensure that all daily and monthly deadlines were met to ensure payments were made on time and reported accurately for Accounts Payable month-end closing.

Staff Accountant

Alameda Corridor-East

February 2001 to May 2005

Processed high volume of Accounts Payables and Receivables

- All accounts payables functions (received/processed invoices)
- Checked for accuracies and approvals, coded and keyed all entries
- Provided assistance to department managers in establishing and complying with budgeted expenditures
- Internal and external audit preparations
- Processed weekly check runs for the department
- Maintained computerized accounting controls to assure the validity of data
- Prepared month-end closing: revenue and expense accruals, fixed asset
- · Bank reconciliations
- Processed Expense budgets
- · Posted receivables
- Collections, maintained cash applications
- Billed customer service and provided the invoices including processing reconciliations

Education

BA in Finance

Cal Poly Pomona

Skills

- Accounts Payable
- · Accounts Receivable
- AP
- Invoice
- Concur
- Time Management
- Excel
- Data Entry
- Accounting
- GAAP
- Journal Entries
- JD Edwards
- Bank Reconciliation
- · Microsoft Dynamics GP
- Office Management
- General Ledger Accounting

- Internal Audits
- QuickBooks
- Accounting Software

Certifications and Licenses

Commission - Notary

April 2018 to April 2022

Additional Information

Computer Skills: Proficient in Microsoft applications; Excel, Word,

Access and Power Point

Accounting Software: JD Edwards, Intuit Fundware, QuickBooks Pro, Oracle and Intuit PC Payroll/EPCOR

Great Plains and Jenark